Hello, and welcome back.
欢迎回来
So, here are my solutions for the exercises I had you do on loading image data.
下面说说我是怎么加载图像数据的
Here, I had you define some transforms and then load the actual dataset with
练习的要求是定义一些转换
image folder and then turn that into a data loader
使用 ImageFolder 加载实际数据集
using this torch utils data loader class.
然后使用 torch.utils.DataLoader 类变成 dataloader
So, here, I chose a couple transforms.
这里涉及到了几个转换方式
So, first, I'm resizing the images to be 255 by 255 squares.
首先将图像变成 255 x 255 正方形
So, basically, even if your image is actually a rectangle,
即使图像是长方形
then this will resize it to be square with 255 pixels on each size.
也会变成正方形 每边有 255 个像素
The first transform I used was resize.
第一个转换是 resize
So, this resizes your images to be squares with 255 pixels on each side.
resize 将图像变成正方形 每边有 255 个像素
So, even if your original image is a rectangle,
即使原始图像是长方形
this will change it into a square.
它也会将图像变成正方形
Then, I did a center crop with 224 pixels.
然后调用 CenterCrop 并传入 224
So, this crops a square out of the center of the image with 224 pixels on each side.
表示在图像中心裁剪出正方形 每边是 224 像素
Then, I convert it into a tensor which we can then use in our networks.
然后转换为可以传入网络里的张量
With the transform defined,
定义好 transform 后
we can pass that into this image folder and along
将 transform 传入这个 ImageFolder
with the path to our dataset and that creates a dataset object.
并传入数据集的路径 从而创建一个 dataset 对象
Then, with the dataset object,
然后将 dataset 对象
we can pass that to data loader.
传入 DataLoader
So, this will give us back a generator were we actually can get our images and labels.
返回一个生成器 我们可以从中获取图像和标签
So, here, I just chose a batch size of 32 and this shuffle set to true.
将批次大小设为 32 并将 shuffle 设为 True
So, basically, every time you loop through the generator again like multiple times,
这样的话
every time you do that,
每次遍历生成器
it'll randomly shuffle the images and labels.
它将随机重排图像和标签
So, that loaded, here's what it looks like.
加载下 效果是这样的
We have a nice little dogs now here.
这是一个小狗图像
So, here, I had you define transforms for our training data and our testing data.
这里需要为训练数据和测试数据定义转换
So, like I was saying before,
正如之前提到的
with training data, you typically want to do data augmentation.
对于训练数据 你通常需要执行数据增强步骤
So, that means rotating it,
也就是旋转
resizing it, flipping it, et cetera,
调整大小 翻转 等等
to create this simulated dataset of more images than we actually have.
从而创建一个模拟数据集 它包含的图像要比实际多很多
Firstly, it just gives you more data to actually train with.
这么做首先有助于用更多数据训练网络
But secondly, it helps the network generalize to images that aren't in the training set.
其次 使网络能够泛化到不在训练集中的图像
So, my transformations here,
这是我的转换
I first chose to do a random rotation with 30 degrees.
首先随机旋转 30 度
So, this is going to rotate in either direction up to 30 degrees.
朝着任一方向旋转 30 度
Then, I did a random resize crop.
然后调用 RandomResizeCrop()
So, this is going to randomly resize the image and then take
即随机调整图像大小
a crop from the center of 224 pixels square.
然后从中心裁剪出大小为 224 个像素的正方形
Then, after that crop, then it do a random horizontal flip.
裁剪之后 调用 RandomHorizontalFlip()
So, it's going to mirror it horizontally and change it to a tensor.
表示水平翻转 然后更改为张量
Then, with the test transforms kind of the same as before resize
测试转换和前面的差不多
it to 255 pixels and then do a center crop 224,
大小调整为 255 像素 然后从中心裁剪出 224 像素的图像
and it finally change it to a tensor.
最后变成张量
Then, here with the train data and test data,
对于训练数据和测试数据
we can pass our data directories and our transforms through this image folder.
传入数据路径和转换
I should actually load the data,
从图像文件夹里加载数据
and then give our loaded data to our data loaders to actually get
将加载的数据放入数据加载器里 从而从数据集中加载数据
our load our datasets so that we can see data from the train loader,
看看训练加载器里的数据 是这样的
it looks like this, and we can see data from our test loader, so like that.
看看测试加载器里的数据 是这样的